<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Page Header on Practical Genomics Workshop</title>
    <link>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Page Header on Practical Genomics Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://practicalgenomics.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prep Work #2 - R Markdown and Unix</title>
      <link>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/preparation/assignment2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/preparation/assignment2/</guid>
      <description>Learning Objectives
Learn some analysis workflows  Obtain data programmatically Use R Markdown documents to communicate analyses  Practice manipulating genomics data using R  Subset data.frames: one or more columns, a block of rows, rows matching a specific column Visualize data: boxplot, barplot, scatterplot  Learn the Unix command line  Tasks
Install software (if not already done)  Slack for troubleshooting help RStudio to provide a rich R environment (must be version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prep Work #1 - Swirl and base R</title>
      <link>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/preparation/assignment1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/preparation/assignment1/</guid>
      <description>The registration form reserves your spot for two weeks. You must complete this assignment or your spot may be forfeited to someone on the waiting list. Afterwards, an additional 4-8 hours of work will be assigned each month leading up to the workshop (e.g. R and Unix tutorials, readings, software installation).
Follow instructions at Swirl Stats  Install R (must be version 3.4.3 or higher) Install RStudio (must be version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/assignments/prepwork-apr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/assignments/prepwork-apr/</guid>
      <description>Preparation Work - April          code{white-space: pre;} pre:not([class]) { background-color: white; }  if (window.hljs) { hljs.configure({languages: []}); hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad(); if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) { window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0); } }  h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARCC</title>
      <link>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/marcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/marcc/</guid>
      <description>Compute resources for this workshop are being generously provided by the Maryland Advanced Research Computing Center (MARCC). Access requires an ssh client and multi-factor authentication using Google Authenticator. You will need to do the following to access MARCC:
Check your email for a workshop specific userid and password (e.g. john-temp@jhu.edu) Install Google Authenticator on your phone (iOS / Android) Add MARCC to Google Authenticator by retrieving and scanning your QR code Test your connection  Log in using ssh by opening Terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation Work - April</title>
      <link>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/assignments/prepwork-apr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/assignments/prepwork-apr/</guid>
      <description>Learning Objectives Learn some analysis workflows  Obtain data programmatically Use R Markdown documents to communicate analyses  Practice manipulating genomics data using R  Subset data.frames: one or more columns, a block of rows, rows matching a specific column Visualize data: boxplot, barplot, scatterplot    Assignment In this assignment, you will look through a gene expression dataset of highly purified human adult and developing fetal pancreatic a and b cells (data from a project that led to this paper doi:10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio</title>
      <link>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/rstudio/</guid>
      <description>
RStudio provides a rich environment to work with R including a syntax-highlighting editor, integrated help and documentation, and interactive literate programming through R Notebooks.
We make extensive use of R Markdown documents for preparation assignments, workshop sessions, and preparing reproducible reports.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack</title>
      <link>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practicalgenomics.github.io/slack/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting help is available from instructors, TAs, and other workshop participants in the #questions channel of the Practical Genomics Slack team. Read about other ways scientists are using this messaging tool.
Create an account  Note: contact us for an invitation if you don’t have an @jhmi.edu @jhu.edu or @carnegiescience.edu email  Install the computer and phone apps to ensure you receive notification alerts  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>